AKSHAY G

Front-End Developer | JavaScript | React | Html | Css

+91 **87 54 070533 akshayg2422**@gmail.com **Gummidipoondi**, Chennai

SUMMARY

Persevering learner and diligent team player with 3.2 years of experience specialising in UI development using the React library. Skilled software engineer with expertise in AI-powered recruiting applications, HRMS, ticket management, educational timeline systems, and ERP applications. You can view my portfolio here.

PROJECTS

INTRVU SPACE — Hiring Application (AI)

https://www.intrvu.space/

• intrvu SPACE helps you conduct automated Interviews, Generate Reports, and Approve Candidates end to end with zero manual effort.

Contribution: Landing page, Login, OTP, Corporate flow, CRUD candidate flow, Settings, Job seeker flow, Report

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

Zeny Q — HRMS

https://www.zenuq.com/

• Employee management application with features like attendance and payroll management.

Contribution: Api integration and data normalisation, Salary slip.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, push notification

Quanta TMS — Ticket Management Solution

https://www.quantatms.in/

• Enhances task and ticket management for improved collaboration.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Individual chats, Group chats, Task, Ticket, Association, Feeds, Events

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

Quanta EDAT — EduTech Application

https://www.quantaedat.com/

• Offers comprehensive programming courses with practical tasks and mock interviews

Contribution: Course CRUD, Tasks, Topics, Schedule Interview, Online Sessions **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

NS Instruments - FG — Finished Goods Management

• Optimises inventory control with streamlined stock and product management.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Dispatch request, Stock request and Paginated Listing **Tech Stack:** React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification

EXPERIENCE

React JS Developer - 02/2021 - 03/2024

Leora Infotech Private Limited - Gummidipoondi, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design and development
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

Data Provisioning Executive - 01/2019 - 11/2019

Tenth Planet Technologies - Mount Road, Chennai.

• Provide customised enterprise IT solutions, centred around open source software, troubleshoot issues, ensure compliance.

Process Associate - 04/2017 - 11/2017

String Information Services - Saidapet, Chennai.

• Mortgage Process Outsourcing (MPO) - tailored solutions, optimise and streamline mortgage processes, enhance efficiency, reduce costs.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Git, GitHub, Bit bucket, Rest, Axios, Fetch, Scss, Firebase, i18n-js, Jitsi, validate.js, React-player, React-photo-view, React-DND, React-Select

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science - 2013 - 2016

Shree Chandraprabhu Jain College Minjur, Chennai.

XII (HSS) - 2011 -2013

St.Marys Matric Hr Sec Chinthala Kuppam, Gummidipoondi.

X (SSLC) - 2010 - 2011

Shanthiniketan Matric Hr Sec New Gummidipoondi.

LANGUAGES

Tamil: Mother Tongue **English:** Professional (Conversationally fluent)

Malayalam: Conversationally fluent Hindi: Writing and Reading